JAEYOUNG (Jake) LEE

LG Apt 110-2002, Yongsan-gu Ichon-dong, Seoul, South Korea, 04427 T: +8210-6389-3332 / E: jaketheturtle555@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Specialized in Organic Chemistry and researched functionality of azaborine compounds. Worked independently and presented master's thesis. Have strong quantitative and analytic skills to solve problems. Passionate to incorporate Chemistry knowledge in the computer science field in the future.

EDUCATION

JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY (Baltimore, MD)

Master of Arts in Chemistry

Aug 2017 - May 2018

Master's Thesis: Investigation of Functionality and Polymerizability of BN 2-Vinylnaphthalene

Bachelor of Arts in Chemistry with ACS credit

Aug 2014 – May 2018

Cumulative GPA: 3.73 / 4.0

4 consecutive semesters of Deans List

Departmental Honors, Chemistry

Relevant course work: Intermediate Programming (C & C++), Computation and Programming for Material Scientists and Engineers, Computational Chemistry, Linear Algebra

KOREA INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL (Seoul, Korea)

Jan 2008 - May 2014

Work Experience

Translator, 106th MEDICAL DETACHMENT, THE US ARMY

Oct 2018 – May 2020

- -Worked in the US army as a Korean Augmentation to the United States Army (KATUSA) to fulfill my duty as a Korean citizen
- -Conveyed information and mediated communication during food inspections, discussion and showcase

Undergrad. Researcher, KLAUSEN LAB, JOHNS HOPKINS UNIV

May 2015 – May 2018

- -Conducted research regularly under my graduate student mentor, Heidi van de Wouw, and studied about projects involving azaborine chemistry
- -Performed various laboratory techniques including air-free synthesis, purification and characterization

Research Intern, NEW DRUG LAB, HANDOK PHARMACETICALS

Jul – Aug 2015

- -Tasked under Han Bok Lee to conduct research about new drugs for diabetes
- -Synthesized and purified candidates for the new drugs and collaborated with biology lab for target testing

PUBLICATION

- 1. H. L. van de Wouw, **J. Y. Lee**, E. C. Awuyah, R. S. Klausen, "A BN Aromatic Ring Strategy for Tunable Hydroxyl Content in Polystyrene," *Angew. Chem.*, **2017**, 57, 1673-1677.
- 2. H. L. van de Wouw*, **J. Y. Lee***, R. S. Klausen, "Free Radical Polymerization of Green Azaborine Vinyl Monomer," *Chem. Commun.*, **2017**, 53, 7262-7265.
- 3. H. L. van de Wouw, **J. Y. Lee**, M. A. Siegler, R. S. Klausen, "Innocent BN bond substitution in anthracene derivatives," *Org. Biomol. Chem.*, **2016**, 14, 3256-3263.

AWARDS

CERTIFICATE (IBM 2020 CALL FOR CODE KOREA HACKATHON)

Jun 2020

- -Participated in creating solutions for COVID-19 as a project designer and front-end coder
- -Designed a donation app that individuals can easily donate and supply necessities to an organization

CERTIFICATE OF ACHIEVEMENT (DEPT. OF THE ARMY)

Apr 2019

-Served an exceptional service as a Korean Augmentation to the United States Army (KATUSA) translator for the 65th Medical Brigade capabilities demonstration for host nation partners

PROVOST'S UNDERGRADUATE RESEARCH AWARD (PURA)

Apr 2016

- -Proposed and worked on a research project about polymerizability of an azaborine compound
- -Presented at DREAMS, an event where undergraduates display their projects, in Spring 2017

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Senior KATUSA, 106th MEDICAL DETACHMENT, THE US ARMY

Dec 2019 - May 2020

- -Managed soldiers and took responsibilities as a leader of a Korean Augmentation to the United States Army (KATUSA) company in 106th MEDDET
 - -Worked together with 1SG Nestor for the betterment of mutual relations between the two Armies

Teaching Assistant, CHEMICAL CHIRALITY (ORG. CHEM. LAB)

Jan 2018 - May 2018

- -Helped students to learn basic principles of organic chemistry behind each experiment
- -Taught various laboratory techniques and guided how to design their independent experiment under Dr. Hill's guidance